If you think you know the story... You don't know the man.
Get Rich or Die Tryin' is a drama, crime, music film directed by Jim Sheridan.
A tale of an inner city drug dealer who turns away from
crime to pursue his passion, rap music.
Marcus, played by 50 Cent.
Charlene, played by Joy Bryant.
Majestic, played by Adewale Akinnuoye-Agbaje.
Keryl, played by Omar Benson Miller.
Bama, played by Terrence Howard.
Grandma, played by Viola Davis.
Get Rich or Die Tryin' is a 2005 American crime drama film
directed by Jim Sheridan and written by Terence Winter.
It stars Curtis "50 Cent" Jackson in his feature film acting debut, alongside Terrence Howard, Joy Bryant,
Bill Duke, Adewale Akinnuoye-Agbaje, Omar Benson Miller, Ashley Walters, and Viola Davis.
The film, which contains autobiographical elements from 50 Cent's life, follows his character, Marcus
Grier, a drug dealer who turns away from his criminal life to pursue his passion of rap music.
The film's title is shared with 50 Cent's 2003 debut album of the same name.
Plans for a film starring 50 Cent were revealed in 2004, following
the success of the Get Rich or Die Tryin' album.
It was known during production as Locked and Loaded.
Similar to the 2002  film 8 Mile starring Eminem, which it used as a template, the film
took inspiration from 50 Cent's childhood experiences as a drug dealer.
Filming began on April 11, 2005, and ended in June of that same year.
The filming locations included New York City, Canada (in Toronto
and Wasaga Beach) and Ireland (in Bray and Dublin).
Originally scheduled for a 2006 release, Get Rich or Die Tryin' had its world premiere at Grauman's Chinese Theatre in
Hollywood on November 2, 2005, and was released in the United States by Paramount Pictures on November 9.
The film initially received negative reviews from critics and was a financial
disappointment, grossing $46.5 million on a budget of $40 million.
However, it has gained a cult following especially for its
soundtrack and remained a standout in 50 Cent's career.
The film explores themes of career, street gang, loss
of loved one, rapper, attempted murder.
The tone is emotional.